# 尝尝让我师父一直念念不忘的
Let's taste this delicacy that my master could not forget
# 吃一个想俩吃俩想仨的
He wants to eat as many as he can
# 就差肘子
It could be better if we have the Jokbal
# 韭菜虾皮卷煎饼
shrimp skin and Chinese chive wrap
# 煎饼现成的买就行 山东的煎饼
You can find the Jianbing at food store, Shandong(a Chinese province)’s Jianbing
# 虾皮咱们一定要挑这种自然颜色
For small shrimp, we must pick this kind of shrimp with the natural color
# 不能挑那种愣白的 愣白的不行
Not with those looks very white
# 首先得把虾皮的咸味给它去一去
At first, we need to get rid of the saline taste of the shrimp
# 得洗一洗
We need to wash
# 它再干净 它底下也有沙子
Even it looks like clean, but the bottom still leaves sands.
# 捞 一定拿手捞出来 底下一层沙子
Catch them with your hand, you can see there is a layer of sands on the bottom.
# 你不信你看底儿
See the bottom
# 看见没有网友们 你看看 再来一遍
See it my friend, see. Wash a second time.
# 这个洗到什么时候为止
When can we finish washing?
# 一会您尝尝 它没有太多咸味了
You could taste later; it is not that salty (then we are done).
# 虾皮洗的要快 不能泡
We must wash the shrimp fast, not soak in the water.
# 把那鲜味咸味泡干净了也不行 动作要快
It could not be good if we get rid of all the salty and umami flavor. We need to be fast.
# 这行了 没问题
Ok, now is good.
# 您看虾皮洗完了 咱们切点葱
After washing shrimp, let’s cut up some green onions.
# 搁在一边备料
Put aside as prepare
# 切好了以后点火
Now we turn on the cooktop
# 把这虾皮攥攥 把这水攥出去
Clench the shrimp, get the water out of shrimp
# 咱们把这虾皮 这叫焙 干焙
Now we need to dry the shrimp, it calls toast.
# 不放油 焙干 焙干香气就出来了
No oil, just toast them, the aroma would come out
# 把这水气给它焙出去 让它酥脆
We need to dry them too, which makes them be more crispy
# 咱这虾皮这样焙干也行
We can toast the shrimp in this way
# 搁在托盘里搁烤箱里烤也可以
or you can put them in the baking tray and put it in the oven to toast
# 已经支棱了 开始松散了 一粒是一粒
the shrimps have been stood up. Now they are separated, one by one.
# 一定小火给它焙干了
It must use low heat to toast it.
# 师父您看香味出来了吧
Master, the aroma has come out
# 现在闻的全是虾米皮味
All I smell is the aroma of shrimp.
# 海鲜味
Seafood flavor
# 差不多了 好关火
Almost down, turn it off
# 出锅
Take it out of the pan
# 咱们先耗点葱油
Let’s make some green onion oil
# 耗葱油是增加它的香味
The green onion oil can add its aroma
# 一般做韭菜是这样
We usually do that when we cook chives.
# 做韭菜的东西不能搁生葱
When cooking chives, we cannot add any fresh green onions
# 炸点葱油特别好
It could be better to make some green onion oil.
# 因为 搁这生葱和韭菜一串味
The flavor would be tainted if we put the chives and the fresh green onion together.
# 两个都是比较冲的味道
Both of them have the pungent smell.
# 耗着葱油
While making the onion oil,
# 咱们这儿切两刀韭菜
Now we are going to cut chives.
# 韭菜的头儿咱们不要
We do not need the end.
# 尽量多使点叶子的部分
Use the part of leaves as many as possible
# 这就够了
That’s all
# 在这跟我们网友说一下
Now we need to remind our frends that
# 入伏的韭菜就不要吃了 韭菜发臭
It is better not to eat the chives at the hottest summer. They are stinky.
# 香气出来了
Now the aroma comes out
# 小点火 咱把这个葱别糟蹋
Turn it down. We could not waste the green onion.
# 都捞出来 留着待会炒菜使
Get all onions out, we need them to be used later.
# 关键步骤 火停着呢（最小火）
Attention! We turn it off (or keep the flame at lowest level)
# 这个油是热的
The oil is hot
# 把这个辣椒炝一下
Now put the pepper into the oil.
# 然后把辣椒捞出去 炸点辣椒油
Then get out the pepper. We make some pepper oil.
# 要呲 一呲这香气就出来了
Must hear the sound, “chi”, it helps release the aroma.
# 用热油呲韭菜和虾皮
Now we put the hot oil on the shrimp and chives.
# 这是一个倒呲油的方法 叫炝
This way is called Qiang (transient fried)
# 这个虾皮刚才咱们已经焙干了
The shrimp now is dry.
# 这一呲油
By the way Qiang
# 韭菜的香味和油的香味儿
The favor of chives and aroma of oil
# 全都能吃到虾米皮里边
All in the shrimp
# 吃油了以后 也透明了 也酥脆了
Shrimp with oil would be more transparent and more crispy
# 韭菜也不会有烂韭菜的味
The chives would not be tasted like be decayed
# 盐呢 要不要 刚才洗的有点咸味
How about salt? Do we need to add some salts? We left some salt when we washed the shrimp
# 所以其它的调料就不用加了
Thus, we do not need to add extra seasonings
# 你看我给大家准备了一个食盒
Look, I prepare a bento box for us.
# 有虾皮 有煎饼
Shrimp and Jianbing
# 然后有彩椒 还有尖椒
And color pepper, and chili pepper
# 还有小葱 还有生菜
And green onion, and lettuce
# 尝尝让我师父一直念念不忘的
Let's taste this delicacy that my master could not forget
# 韭菜煎饼卷虾皮
Chives and shrimp skin wrap
# 真得先跟你大爷 直接给他搁嘴里边
Give your Da Ye first, put into his mouth directly
# 看看大爷什么表情
See Da Ye’s face
# 谢谢朝辉 谢谢二伯
Thanks Chaohui, thanks Er Bai
# 大爷吃 大爷怎么样啊
Da Ye, how do you feel
# 好吃
good
# 这咸味刚刚好 正好
The salty flavor is exactly fine.
# 最有特点的 搁了点辣椒
The most special part is adding the pepper.
# 我吃别的就没搁辣椒
I have never added pepper when I eat other food.
# 师父尝尝
Have a taste, master
# 一口就下去了 酥香
I can wolf down it; it is so crispy.
# 没有虾米皮的腥味
No the stinky smell of shrimp
# 它这个调料的运用 非常恰当
Every seasoning is used properly
# 我说最突出的就这点辣椒用的好
The best is the use of pepper
# 它每种过味道提出来的恰到好处
Every kind of flavor is accurate to be embodied.
# 吃一个想俩吃俩想仨的
The one is not enough
# 再来一个
I want one more
# 第二个就是生菜卷虾皮
Second one is lettuce and shrimp wrap
# 看师父这个嘴
Look master’s mouth
# 有荤有素 营养搭配
There are meat as well as vegetables, keeping the balance of nutrition
# 就差肘子了
It could be better if we have the Jokbal
# 咱们今天是为了吃的素一点
Today we want to have more vegetables
# 真的 大爷说的对
Yes, Da Ye are truly correct.
# 吃完这个 我真是从心里边说什么
After eating this, I really want to say something from my heart.
# 还想吃 不是
Don’t you want more?
# 有没有肉啊
No meat?!
# 再卷片儿肉吃更香了
Wrap one piece of meat would be more delicious